Be careful.
小心
- He's strong. - Got it.
-他很厉害 -知道了
Wh... What is going on so early in the morning?
一大早的 发生了什么事吗?
It doesn't seem like anyone's here.
看起来这里应该没人
I can't tell with all this junk.
垃圾这么多 我实在分辨不出来
Throw everything out!
把所有东西都搬出去
Jeez, what is this all about?
天啊 这究竟是怎么回事?
He escaped.
他逃跑了
- What? - Gardar escaped.
-什么? -哥达逃跑了
Is there any other reason why they would be ransacking our shed?
不然他们还会为了什么原因 这么仔细地搜查我们的小屋?
Arnheid!
阿奴纳
Wait, Einar!
等等 埃纳尔
Stop for a second. Einar!
等一下 埃纳尔
If Gardar escaped,
如果哥达逃跑了
he will definitely try to find Arnheid again.
他一定会想办法再去找阿奴纳
What will you do once you're with Arnheid?
找到阿奴纳之后你打算怎么办?
Are you going to chase Gardar away?
你打算赶跑哥达吗?
I don't know.
我不知道
But...
但是
there must be
一定有什么
something that
我能帮上
I can do to help Arnheid!
阿奴纳的地方
Arnheid!
阿奴纳
That's not him.
不是他
It's not Gardar.
不是哥达
It's two slaves.
是两个奴隶
What were their names...?
他们叫什么名字?
Oh, they work for the master...
他们是为主人工作的...
Thorfinn and Einar?
托尔芬和埃纳尔吗?
Yes, that's right.
对 没错
What are they here for?
他们来这里做什么?
What should we do, Boss? Should we chase them away?
我们该怎么办 老大? 该把他们赶走吗?
No, don't mind them.
不用 别管他们
Let them be.
随他们去吧
Um...
呃...
Arnheid.
阿奴纳
Yes...
是...
It's about Gardar, right?
与哥达有关 对吧?
You knew?
你知道了?
Yes.
对
I...
是我...
let him escape.
帮助他逃跑的
I cut
我砍断了
Gardar's rope.
哥达的绳索
Gardar
哥达
killed the guard.
杀了客人
And I thought we were
我原本以为
both going to die.
我们两个都会死在那里
I...
我...
After that,
之后
the other guards
其他客人
rushed out
立刻冲了过来
but Gardar
但哥达
killed them all.
把他们全都杀了
The guards again...
又是那些客人...
This is bad... really bad.
大事不妙...这真的很糟糕
Einar.
埃纳尔
The guards are watching us.
客人正在监视着我们
Act like you're helping with the dishes
装着一副你在帮忙洗碗的样子
and get closer to Arnheid.
靠阿奴纳近一点
Stay calm
冷静些
and tell us what the situation is.
告诉我们事发经过
During the fight,
在打斗的时候
Gardar also suffered a bad injury.
哥达也受伤惨重
Then the two of us ran away in the rain
我们冒着大雨逃跑
until we got to the old master's house.
一直跑到了老主人家
But
但是
while I was treating his wound,
我在治疗哥达伤势的时候
Gardar lost consciousness.
哥达失去了意识
He was so heavy and I couldn't carry him.
他太重了 我搬不动他
But
但是
I was somehow able to hide him.
我想办法把他藏起来了
So Gardar is here?
所以哥达在这里?
Yes.
对
The old master helped us out.
老主人帮了我们一把
Snake and his men came right after that.
蛇和他的手下立刻就赶过来了
They seem to think
他们似乎认为
that Gardar escaped
哥达逃掉了
and is hiding somewhere.
目前躲在某个地方
They're in the main house
他们现在在主屋
waiting for Gardar to come and see me.
等着哥达来这里找我
Snake and two other men.
蛇和其他两个人
Why...?
为什么?
Why did you do something so dangerous on your own?
你为什么要自己一个人 做出这么危险的事?
You said you'd let the storm pass
你说过 为了你的孩子
for the sake of your child!
你会等待着风暴过去
Why...?
为什么?
A dream...
一个梦想...
I couldn't help
我无法控制自己
but dream, I guess.
追逐这个梦想 应该是这样吧
About my unborn child,
关于我未出世的孩子
Gardar,
哥达
and our family...
和我们的家庭
I thought
我以为
that maybe things were back to normal.
或许一切可以恢复正常
Back to...
回到...
Back to normal.
从前那样
His eyes
他的眼神
used to be filled with so much confidence.
以前总是充满自信
And now...
而现在...
We're absolutely pitiful.
我们真的太可怜了
We lost Hjalti and yet
我们失去了贾赫提
the two of us are pitifully
而我们两人仍然很可悲地
trying to hang on to life.
试图活下去
And despite that
尽管如此
we're still dreaming.
我们还是想追求梦想
How are Gardar's wounds?
哥达的伤势如何?
Did he stop bleeding?
他止血了吗?
The right side of his chest
他的胸口右侧
was bleeding so much.
失血严重
When I hid him
我把他藏起来的时候
it was still bleeding.
伤口仍然在流血
We don't have much time.
我们的时间不多了
Arnheid...
阿奴纳
Are you ready to
你准备好...
share the same fate as Gardar?
与哥达承担共同的命运了吗?
If you want to spend your life with Gardar,
如果你想与哥达共度此生
you'll have to run away with him.
你就得跟他一起逃跑
But you are with child.
但你怀有身孕
No doubt, the journey will be difficult.
这段路途势必会很辛苦
But if you still want to do it,
但如果你仍想这么做
I will help you.
我会帮助你
At this point,
此时此刻
that is the only way.
也只剩这条路了
The only way, huh?
只剩这条路吗?
I will help too. With two people,
我也会帮忙 有两个人的话
maybe we can think of a plan.
我们或许可以想出一个办法
Thorfinn...
托尔芬
Ouch!
好痛
Don't sleep.
别打瞌睡
The next time you take your eyes off of Arnheid, I'll break your nose.
你再让阿奴纳离开你视线的话 我就会打断你的鼻梁
Yes, I'm sorry.
好的 我错了
Who is it?
是谁?
Um, I should start preparing lunch soon.
我该开始准备午餐了
Take the equipment and make it outside.
把需要的用具拿走 去外面煮
You're a decoy. Stay where people can see you.
你是诱饵 待在别人看得见你的地方
Yes, I understand.
好的 我明白了
What a sad situation they are in.
他们的处境也太令人难过了
Don't you think so, Snake?
你不这么觉得吗 蛇?
"Slaves
“奴隶
were destined to become slaves because they were born inferior."
注定会成为奴隶 这是因为他们生来就是条贱命”
That is what people say.
大家都这么说
As if everyone was meant to play a certain role.
仿佛每个人注定要扮演某种角色
But I don't think so.
但我不这么认为
Slaves were just unlucky.
奴隶只是运气不好
It's as simple as that.
就只是这样而已
If luck wasn't on our side, you and I
如果幸运之神不是站在我们这边
may have ended up as slaves ourselves.
你和我也有可能会成为奴隶
So what?
那又怎样?
That has nothing to do with this.
跟这件事一点关系都没有
Five of our men were killed.
我们有五个人被杀了
I won't be satisfied until I kill that bastard.
只有在杀了那个混蛋之后 我才会心满意足
If I let him get away with killing my subordinates
如果我让他在杀了我的五名手下之后 仍可逃之夭夭
I'd have no right to carry a sword anymore.
我再也不配把剑带在身上
Well then, just get rid of your sword.
那么 就把你的剑丢了吧
That sword
那把剑
is not from around here, that much I know.
不是来自于这个地方 这点我还知道
I assume you have your reasons for ending up here.
我想你最后在这里待了下来 也是有你自己的原因
But unless you get rid of your sword,
但除非你摆脱你的剑
you won't be able to eliminate the root of the problem.
不然你将无法根除你的问题
That's enough talking, Gramps.
你说够了吧 老头子
It's time for old people to take a nap.
老人家也该睡午觉了
I will give you my field.
我会把我的田地给你
Cultivate the land
开垦这片土地
and try growing life.
试着培育出新的生命
It's much better than waving around a sword.
这比与剑为伍的日子要好的多了
I can't
我再也无法
stand or walk anymore.
站立或走动了
I will die soon.
我活不久了
Take this chance to start living a normal life.
把握这个机会 开始过着一个正常人的生活吧
I owe you
这是我欠你的
for having you read the Bible to me, after all.
毕竟你常念圣经给我听
Now is not the time for this nonsense.
现在不是说这种话的时候
As if I'd work on a field...
一副我会愿意在田里工作的样子...
- Boss! - Huh?
-老大 -怎么了?
There's somebody there.
那里有个人
Over there. The third tree from the back.
在那里 从后面数第三棵树
I think that's him in the shadow of the tree.
我认为那个躲在树荫下的人就是他
All right.
好的
They're out.
他们出去了
One horse...
一匹马
two horses, three horses. Okay, that's all of them.
两匹马、三匹马 好的 他们都出去了
I'm counting on you, Einar.
就指望你了 埃纳尔
Spread out.
散开
Chase him from different directions and viewpoints.
从不同的方向包抄他
Old Master!
老主人
Sorry, but I'm going to borrow a horse and wagon.
抱歉 但我得向您借马和马车
I promise I will work and pay you back for it.
我保证我一定会用劳力偿还
Stop worrying about such trivial things.
别担心那种小事了
More importantly, put me on the wagon as well.
更重要的是 也把我抬上马车
If I'm on it, nobody will question you
如果我也在马车上 只要在农场的范围之内
while you're on this farm.
就不会有人问东问西
No, but...
不行啊 这种事...
I can't get you involved in this.
我不能把您牵扯进来
I'm already involved in this.
我早就牵扯进来了
Stop bickering and help me out already.
别吵了 快帮我一把
Yes. Thank you so much.
好的 实在太感谢您了
That bastard is trying to escape into the forest.
那个混蛋正试图逃进森林里
We can't navigate those woods on horses.
我们无法骑着马穿越森林
Catch up to him! Don't let him inside.
快点追上他 别让他跑进去
Damn it! It's so far!
该死 好远啊
He's still alive.
他还活着
She did a good job.
她做得很好
But he's as cold as stone.
但他跟石头一样冰冷
He lost too much blood.
他失血过多
Please hang in there.
一定要撑下去啊
He's fast.
他跑得好快
No matter how you look at it, he's not running like a wounded person.
不管怎么看 他都完全不像是个受伤的人
Spider, Badger!
蜘蛛、獾
Keep chasing him.
继续追他
But don't get too close.
但不要靠得太近
If he's Gardar,
如果他是哥达
you two won't be able to handle him.
你们两个没办法对付他
I'll send backup later.
我等一下会派后援过来
Until then, keep on chasing him. Got it?
在那之前 继续追下去 懂吗?
I'm counting on you.
这件事就交给你们了
What?! Hey, Boss! Where are you...?
什么?老大 你要去哪里?
The wagon is ready. Let's rush to the southern border.
马车准备好了 我们快点赶去南方边界
Once we're in a different country,
一旦我们到了另一个国家
it'll be hard for the guests to chase us.
那些客人要追我们的话就有困难了
I'll part ways at some point as a diversion.
我中途会和你们分开以声东击西
I'll try to lure as many as I can.
我会尽力把他们全都引开
Old Master, please accompany us until the end of the farm.
老主人 请陪我们到农场的边界
Understood.
明白了
I didn't hear any horses.
我没听到马匹的声音
He got off his horse and ran here?
他下了马 然后跑来这里?
I see...
原来是这样
He's unconscious, huh?
他失去意识了?
No wonder I couldn't sense his presence.
难怪我无法察觉到他的存在
Thorfinn...
托尔芬
Just so you know, Thorfinn.
托尔芬 我警告你
Negotiation is not an option.
这里没有商量的余地
Hand over Gardar without a fight.
乖乖地把哥达交出来
Or else
不然
I'll cut you down.
我会宰了你
There are three pursuers.
总共有三个人在追捕哥达
But right now, Snake is the only one here.
但现在只有蛇在这里
I don't sense the other two.
我没感受到其他两人的存在
If I can somehow stop him,
如果我能想办法阻止他
we can still run away.
我们仍有逃命的机会
Dodge his sword and land a blow to his chin.
躲开他的剑 朝他的下巴重击一拳
Are you going to fight, Thorfinn?
托尔芬 你打算出手吗?
Oh well, I guess it can't be helped in this situation.
我想在这种情况之下 任何人都无能为力
You're genuinely trying to help someone.
你是真心想要助人
You're using your fists for a just cause.
你用你的拳头寻求正义
That being said,
话说回来
your opponent has his own just cause as well.
你的对手也有他自己的正当理由
What will you do, Thorfinn?
你打算怎么办 托尔芬?
Will you uphold nonviolence regardless?
你无论如何都会坚持不用暴力吗?
Or will you fight for the sake of helping others?
还是你会为了助人而战呢?
Which one leads to the path of a true warrior?
哪一种选择 会引领你走向真正的战士之路?
There's no time to think.
没时间思考了
Look, right in front of you.
你看 迫在眉睫了
You think you can win against him with your head in the clouds?
你如此脱离现实 你认为你有办法赢过他吗?
What a strange stance.
好奇怪的姿势
It's not a spear or an axe.
那不是矛也不是斧头
A sword?
一把剑?
No...
不对...
''Way Home.''
家路
Subtitle translation by: Kiko Morita
字幕翻译:朱未耒